<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title type="text">Blog Bitix</title>
    <subtitle type="text">Blog sobre el lenguaje de programación Java y la distribución GNU/Linux que uso habitualmente, Arch Linux, lo que aprendo sobre el software libre, la programación web y otros temas relacionados con la tecnología y la informática. El contenido puede contener trazas de asuntos fuera de tema.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/index.xml"/>
    <link href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/" />
    <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/en/posts/</id>
    <updated>2020-11-01T18:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <icon>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/assets/favicon.ico</icon>
    <logo>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/assets/images/blog-bitix.svg</logo>
    <rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</rights>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/07/4-ways-to-make-a-for-loop-in-java/</id>
        <title>4 ways to make a for loop in Java</title>
        <updated>2020-11-01T18:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <published>2020-11-01T18:00:00+01:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/07/4-ways-to-make-a-for-loop-in-java/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>The usual way in Java to do a loop is with a <em>for</em> or <em>while</em> statement but with the addition of iterators in Java 5 it is not necessary to have a variable to keep the index of the loop. Since Java 8, <em>streams</em> have been added that offer other new ways of iterating over the elements of a collection, in the latter case with techniques of functional languages.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/07/4-ways-to-make-a-for-loop-in-java/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="java"/>
            
                <category term="planeta-codigo"/>
            
                <category term="programacion"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2020/09/how-to-buy-a-license-and-activate-windows-10-and-office-2019/</id>
        <title>How to buy a license and activate Windows 10 and Office 2019</title>
        <updated>2020-09-10T22:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <published>2020-09-10T22:00:00+02:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2020/09/how-to-buy-a-license-and-activate-windows-10-and-office-2019/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>Windows 10 and Microsoft Office 2019 are software products with a private license, to use them legally it is necessary to buy a license that allows them to be activated. Resorting to activators of these products to avoid paying the license is not recommended since they are a source of entry for computer viruses with a significant danger to the security of the computer and the importance of the tasks that we currently perform in it, such as purchases or banking inquiries. A 2012 European court ruling allows third-party vendors to offer Windows 10 and Microsoft Office 2019 licenses at significantly cheaper prices to activate these products fully legally.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2020/09/how-to-buy-a-license-and-activate-windows-10-and-office-2019/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="microsoft"/>
            
                <category term="planeta-codigo"/>
            
                <category term="windows"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2015/07/microsoft-does-not-care-if-you-use-windows-or-office-without-a-license/</id>
        <title>Microsoft does not care if you use Windows or Office without a license</title>
        <updated>2017-12-03T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <published>2017-12-03T12:00:00+01:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2015/07/microsoft-does-not-care-if-you-use-windows-or-office-without-a-license/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>If Microsoft wished there would be no Windows users using it without the corresponding license. But they consents, they does not care that for a personal use it pirated. A few days after July 29, Windows 10 will appear on the file sharing networks and download pages, also a few days later a program will appear that avoids the validation system as has happened with previous versions.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2015/07/microsoft-does-not-care-if-you-use-windows-or-office-without-a-license/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="microsoft"/>
            
                <category term="opinion"/>
            
                <category term="planeta-codigo"/>
            
                <category term="software-libre"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/05/download-and-install-windows-10-step-by-step-from-scratch/</id>
        <title>Download and install Windows 10 step by step from scratch</title>
        <updated>2020-11-01T12:30:00+01:00</updated>
        <published>2017-05-09T22:30:00+02:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/05/download-and-install-windows-10-step-by-step-from-scratch/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>A virus, <em>bloatware</em> pre-installed on many laptops, or after installing and uninstalling programs in Windows can cause the computer to slow down, display error messages, or a virus to encrypt personal files. In these cases, a simple, fast and reliable common solution to use the computer normally again is to reinstall Windows 10 from scratch. It is not complicated but for a user with little computer knowledge it is not an easy task. In this article I explain how to download and install the Windows 10 operating system step by step from scratch for free.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/05/download-and-install-windows-10-step-by-step-from-scratch/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="microsoft"/>
            
                <category term="planeta-codigo"/>
            
                <category term="software"/>
            
                <category term="windows"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/05/4-free-office-suites-alternatives-to-microsoft-office/</id>
        <title>4 free office suites alternatives to Microsoft Office</title>
        <updated>2017-04-14T12:15:00+02:00</updated>
        <published>2017-04-14T12:15:00+02:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/05/4-free-office-suites-alternatives-to-microsoft-office/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>Microsoft Office is the office suite with a great margin of difference in the usage quota with the next option on Windows systems. It is very complete and includes more features that most users know but it is also a more expensive option than other alternatives that are free without having anything to envy for most users and use cases.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/05/4-free-office-suites-alternatives-to-microsoft-office/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="gnu-linux"/>
            
                <category term="microsoft"/>
            
                <category term="software"/>
            
                <category term="software-libre"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/01/windows-10-and-office-2016-as-easy-to-use-without-license-as-always/</id>
        <title>Windows 10 and Office 2016 as easy to use without license as always</title>
        <updated>2020-09-26T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <published>2017-04-08T11:00:00+02:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/01/windows-10-and-office-2016-as-easy-to-use-without-license-as-always/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>I commented in an article that it is surprising that Microsoft with the capacity that it has and being the devices connected to Internet mostly is not able to avoid using its software without license. I&rsquo;m about to see if with Windows 10 and Office 2016 it&rsquo;s still as easy to use as always. I will also have a sample of the unfair fame of Windows but that allows Microsoft for the bloatware that the device manufacturers pre-installs with its operating system.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2016/01/windows-10-and-office-2016-as-easy-to-use-without-license-as-always/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="microsoft"/>
            
                <category term="opinion"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/01/script-to-install-arch-linux-easy-fast-unattended-automated-and-customizable-way/</id>
        <title>Script to install Arch Linux easy, fast, unattended, automated and customizable way</title>
        <updated>2017-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <published>2017-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</published>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/01/script-to-install-arch-linux-easy-fast-unattended-automated-and-customizable-way/"/>
        <author><name>picodotdev</name></author>
        <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <p><strong>Arch Linux is one of the most customizable GNU/Linux distributions but whose installation requires reading a good amount of documentation, guides or manuals to know what commands to execute step by step in the <em>prompt</em> of the system in which it leaves you the installation medium. Some users choose a distribution like Antergos, KaOS or Manjaro with a graphical installer and guided simply by the fact that they do not face Arch Linux installation from the command line. Still, executing a command and waiting for it to finish before entering another is slow and requires attention.</strong></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://picodotdev.github.io/blog-bitix/2017/01/script-to-install-arch-linux-easy-fast-unattended-automated-and-customizable-way/"></a></p>

        ]]>
        </content>
        
            
                <category term="gnu-linux"/>
            
                <category term="planeta-codigo"/>
            
                <category term="software-libre"/>
            
        
    </entry>
    
</feed>